A Guide to the Musical Manuscripts of Howald T. Bailey,
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Musical Manuscripts of Howald T. Bailey
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11781
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
They were transferred from the Music Library, University of Virginia, through Jane Penner to Special Collections on January 16, 2000.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the music compositions and manuscripts of Howald Tucker Bailey (1917-?), chiefly written for piano, with occasional orchestral and vocal pieces, ca. 75 items, ca. 1937-1958.
Contents List
- Air, 1938
- Air, n.d., Oversize.
- Album-Leaf [no. 230] and Gavotte [no. 231], n.d., Oversize.
- Along a Shady Lane, n.d., Oversize.
- Arabesque, 1954, Oversize.
- Can This Be Spring [no. 246], n.d., Oversize.
- Christmas Lullaby, 1952, Oversize.
- Country Jig and Pastorale, n.d., Oversize.
- Cradle Song, 1940, Oversize.
- Crocus, n.d.
- Farewell [no. 220], 1937
  Oversize.
- Four Moods for Piano (Plus Two), 1958
- Here Where My Love Lies Sleeping, 1941
- Here Where My Love Lies Sleeping, 1941, Oversize.
- I Didn't Catch Your Name, n.d., Oversize.
- Imps at Play, n.d., Oversize.
- Intermezzo [no. 174], n.d., Oversize.
- A Little Folk Song, n.d., Oversize.
- A Little Suite for Two Pianos Piano I, n.d., Oversize.
- A Little Suite for Two Pianos Piano II, n.d., Oversize.
- Lullaby [no. 139] and Solitary Flower (By the Road) [no. 140], n.d., Oversize.
- Lullaby, n.d., Oversize.
- Minuet in Today's Tempo, n.d., Oversize.
- Die Nacht [no. 228] and Country Dance [no. 229], n.d., Oversize.
- The Night Has a Thousand Eyes [no. 165] and Petite Valse [no. 166], n.d., Oversize.
- Old Zip Coon, n.d., Oversize.
- A Prayer, n.d., Oversize.
- Prelude for Orchestra [no. 245], n.d., Oversize.
- Preludium (a la Handel), n.d., Oversize.
- Relijus, n.d., Oversize.
- Roll Along, River [no. 256], n.d., Oversize.
- Rhapsody, Oversize.
- Rhapsody, n.d., Oversize
- Rhapsody, n.d., Oversize.
- Romance(J. Sibelius, Op. 24, no. 9) [no. 72], n.d., Oversize.
- Separation, n.d., Oversize.
- She Is My Lady Fair, n.d., Oversize.
- Sonata in A Major for Violin and Piano [no. 264], n.d., Oversize.
- Sonata in E Minor, n.d., Oversize.
- A Song [no. 138], n.d., Oversize.
- Songs (Without Words!), n.d.
- Sonnet (When I Reflect That Thou Hast Gone from Me), n.d., Oversize.
- Spring Snow, 1941
- Spring Snow, 1941, Oversize.
- Springtime in Old Vienna, n.d., Oversize.
- Thanks to You, n.d., Oversize.
- Tripping the Light Fantastic, n.d., Oversize.
- Twilight, n.d., Oversize.
- Two Miniatures for String Orchestra 1. The Mill 2. Waltz, n.d.
- Two-Part Invention, n.d., Oversize.
- Waltz, n.d., Oversize.
- Waltz in A, n.d., Oversize.
- Waltz in G, n.d., Oversize.
- Waltz Song, n.d., Oversize.
- A Wish, n.d., Oversize.
- Six Moods for Piano, including: Tripping the Light Fantastic, Along the Shady Lane, She is My Lady Fair, Imps at Play, Springtime in Old Vienna, and Minuet in Today's Tempo, n.d.
- Untitled- First Line: How many times you've said, n.d.
- Untitled, n.d.
- Untitled and Fragments, n.d., Oversize.